// Disable F5 key (key code 116) and prevent page refresh
window.addEventListener('keydown', function (e) {
  if (e.keyCode === 116) {
    e.preventDefault();
    // alert("F5 is disabled.");
  }
});


// Fisher-Yates Shuffle Function
function shuffleArray(array) {
  for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
    const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
    [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]];
    array[i].numb = i + 1;
  }
}

// Creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [


  // Word
  {
    question: "What is the keyboard shortcut to insert a new comment in Microsoft Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Alt+C",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Alt+C",
      "Alt+Shift+C",
      "Ctrl+Shift+C",
      "Ctrl+Alt+M"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Word, which view allows you to see how a document will look when it's printed?",
    answer: "Print Layout View",
    options: [
      "Draft View",
      "Print Layout View",
      "Full Screen Reading View",
      "Web Layout View"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which feature in Word allows you to create custom, reusable document elements like cover pages and headers?",
    answer: "Quick Parts",
    options: [
      "WordArt",
      "Quick Parts",
      "Styles",
      "Shapes"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which file format is the default for saving documents in Microsoft Word?",
    answer: "DOCX",
    options: [
      "DOCX",
      "PDF",
      "RTF",
      "TXT"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To remove all formatting from a selected text in Word, which keyboard shortcut is used?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+N",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Space",
      "Ctrl+Shift+Z",
      "Ctrl+Spacebar",
      "Ctrl+Shift+N"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To remove all formatting from a selected text in Word, which keyboard shortcut is used?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+N",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Space",
      "Ctrl+Shift+Z",
      "Ctrl+Spacebar",
      "Ctrl+Shift+N"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which tab in Word contains the commands for adding charts and tables to a document?",
    answer: "Insert",
    options: [
      "Page Layout",
      "Insert",
      "Home",
      "Review"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Microsoft Word, what does the acronym 'BCC' stand for when referring to email options?",
    answer: "Blind Carbon Copy",
    options: [
      "Blind Carbon Copy",
      "Background Color Control",
      "Bold, Center, Copy",
      "Basic Character Control"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the maximum number of columns you can insert into a table in Microsoft Word 2019?",
    answer: "256",
    options: [
      "63",
      "256",
      "32",
      "100"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which feature in Microsoft Word helps you quickly replicate the formatting of one object onto another?",
    answer: "Format Painter",
    options: [
      "Paint Format",
      "Format Painter",
      "Style Painter",
      "Copy Format"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a valid file extension for saving a Word document?",
    answer: ".wrk",
    options: [
      ".docx",
      ".dot",
      ".wrk",
      ".docm"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What does the "Mail Merge" feature in Word allow you to do?`,
    answer: "Merge and print personalized documents",
    options: [
      "Send emails directly from Word",
      "Merge and print personalized documents",
      "Share documents via cloud storage",
      "Create hyperlinks within a document"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `In Word, what is the purpose of the "Find and Replace" feature?`,
    answer: "To search for specific words or phrases and replace them with another",
    options: [
      "To search for and format text",
      "To locate and insert clip art",
      "To search for specific words or phrases and replace them with another",
      "To spell-check a document"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which tab in Word allows you to create and modify tables and charts?`,
    answer: "Insert",
    options: [
      "Insert",
      "Layout",
      "Home",
      "References"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the maximum number of headers or footers you can have in a Word document?`,
    answer: "unlimited",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "unlimited"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which keyboard shortcut is used to split a table in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+T",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Shift+Enter",
      "Alt+Shift+S",
      "Ctrl+Shift+T",
      "Ctrl+Alt+X"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the purpose of the "Thesaurus" feature in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "To provide synonyms and antonyms for selected words",
    options: [
      "To check for document plagiarism",
      "To translate text to other languages",
      "To provide synonyms and antonyms for selected words",
      "To create a table of contents"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `In Word, which view allows you to see how your document will look when it's published on the web?`,
    answer: "Web Layout View",
    options: [
      "Web Layout View",
      "Print Layout View",
      "Draft View",
      "Outline View"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the maximum number of recent documents displayed in the "Recent" section of the Word Start screen by default?`,
    answer: "15",
    options: [
      "10",
      "15",
      "20",
      "25"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `In Word, which option is used to create a clickable link to an external website or email address?`,
    answer: "Hyperlink",
    options: [
      "Hyperlink",
      "Bookmark",
      "Cross-reference",
      "Anchor"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `How can you insert a non-breaking space between words in a Word document?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+Space",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Space",
      "Ctrl+Shift+Space",
      "Alt+Space",
      "Shift+Space"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the keyboard shortcut to quickly switch between open documents in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+Tab",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Tab",
      "Alt+Tab",
      "Ctrl+Page Up",
      "Ctrl+Shift+T"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which keyboard shortcut is used to select the entire document in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+A",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+A",
      "Ctrl+E",
      "Ctrl+D",
      "Ctrl+Z"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the shortcut key for creating a new document in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+N",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+N",
      "Ctrl+O",
      "Ctrl+S",
      "Ctrl+P"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which shortcut key is used to undo the last action in Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+Z",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+U",
      "Ctrl+Z",
      "Ctrl+Y",
      "Ctrl+X"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `To open the "Find and Replace" dialog box in Word, you can use which keyboard shortcut?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+F",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+F",
      "Ctrl+R",
      "Ctrl+H",
      "Ctrl+G"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the shortcut key to insert a new page break in a Word document?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+Enter",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Shift+Enter",
      "Ctrl+P",
      "Ctrl+Enter",
      "Ctrl+J"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which keyboard shortcut allows you to cut selected text or objects in Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+X",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+X",
      "Ctrl+C",
      "Ctrl+V",
      "Ctrl+Z"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `What is the shortcut key to apply or remove bold formatting to selected text in Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+B",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+I",
      "Ctrl+U",
      "Ctrl+B",
      "Ctrl+L"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `Which keyboard shortcut is used to align selected text or objects to the right in Microsoft Word?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+R",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Shift+R",
      "Ctrl+R",
      "Ctrl+T",
      "Ctrl+Shift+T"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: `To close the active document in Word, what is the keyboard shortcut?`,
    answer: "Ctrl+W",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+F4",
      "Alt+F4",
      "Alt+W",
      "Ctrl+W"
    ]
  },

  // Excel

  {
    question: "Which keyboard shortcut is used to create a non-breaking space in Microsoft Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+Space",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Space",
      "Ctrl+Shift+Space",
      "Ctrl+Alt+Space",
      "Alt+Space"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to toggle the 'Show/Hide' feature to display non-printing characters in Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+8",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Shift+S",
      "Ctrl+*",
      "Alt+Shift+N",
      "Ctrl+Shift+8"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the keyboard shortcut to insert a new comment in a Word document?",
    answer: "Alt+Ctrl+M",
    options: [
      "Alt+Ctrl+C",
      "Alt+Shift+M",
      "Ctrl+Alt+I",
      "Alt+Ctrl+M"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key combination is used to select the entire table in Microsoft Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+T",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+T",
      "Ctrl+Shift+T",
      "Alt+T",
      "Alt+Shift+T"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the keyboard shortcut to create a new document in Word without closing the existing one?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+N",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+N",
      "Ctrl+O",
      "Ctrl+Shift+N",
      "Ctrl+Alt+N"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key allows you to switch between the open Word documents?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Tab",
    options: [
      "Alt+Tab",
      "Ctrl+Tab",
      "Alt+Shift+S",
      "Ctrl+Shift+T"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the keyboard shortcut to merge selected cells in a table in Word?",
    answer: "Alt+M",
    options: [
      "Alt+M",
      "Ctrl+M",
      "Ctrl+Shift+M",
      "Alt+Shift+M"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key combination is used to insert a page break in Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Enter",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+Enter",
      "Ctrl+P",
      "Ctrl+Shift+Enter",
      "Ctrl+PageDown"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the keyboard shortcut to format text as subscript in Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+Shift+=",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+=",
      "Ctrl+.",
      "Ctrl+Alt+S",
      "Ctrl+Shift+="
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which keyboard shortcut is used to open the 'Find and Replace' dialog box in Word?",
    answer: "Ctrl+H",
    options: [
      "Ctrl+F",
      "Ctrl+R",
      "Ctrl+H",
      "Ctrl+Shift+F"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does the function VLOOKUP in Excel do?",
    answer: "Searches for a value in a vertical column and returns a corresponding value from another column",
    options: [
      "Searches for a value in a vertical column and returns a corresponding value from another column",
      "Calculates the variance between two datasets",
      "Adds up all the values in a range",
      "Rounds a number to the nearest integer"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which Excel function is used to find the largest value in a range?",
    answer: "MAX",
    options: [
      "MAX",
      "LARGE",
      "BIGGEST",
      "HIGHEST"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, which keyboard shortcut allows you to create a new worksheet within a workbook?",
    answer: "Ctrl + Shift + N",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + N",
      "Ctrl + Shift + N",
      "Alt + N",
      "Shift + W"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'Circular Reference' error in Excel indicate?",
    answer: "A cell references itself, creating an infinite loop",
    options: [
      "A cell references itself, creating an infinite loop",
      "A cell contains an incorrect formula",
      "The worksheet is too large to calculate",
      "Excel is not responding"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, which function is used to count the number of cells in a range that meet a specific condition?",
    answer: "COUNTIF",
    options: [
      "COUNT",
      "SUM",
      "IF",
      "COUNTIF"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'Concatenate' function in Excel do?",
    answer: "Combines text from multiple cells into one cell",
    options: [
      "Adds two numbers",
      "Combines text from multiple cells into one cell",
      "Calculates the product of two values",
      "Divides a cell into multiple cells"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which Excel feature allows you to protect a worksheet from unwanted changes by other users?",
    answer: "Worksheet Locking",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Password Encryption",
      "Worksheet Locking",
      "Workbook Sharing"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'PMT' function in Excel calculate?",
    answer: "The payment for a loan based on a fixed interest rate and number of periods",
    options: [
      "The payment for a loan based on a fixed interest rate and number of periods",
      "The total sum of a range of values",
      "The difference between two dates",
      "The percentage increase in a value"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, what is the result of the formula '=IF(ISBLANK(A1), B1, A1)' if cell A1 is empty?",
    answer: "B1",
    options: [
      "#VALUE!",
      "#REF!",
      "A1",
      "B1"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the maximum number of worksheets you can have in a single Excel workbook?",
    answer: "65,536",
    options: [
      "256",
      "65,536",
      "1,048,576",
      "32,767"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, what does the 'TRIM' function do?",
    answer: "Removes leading and trailing spaces from text",
    options: [
      "Removes leading and trailing spaces from text",
      "Rounds a number to the nearest integer",
      "Converts text to uppercase",
      "Returns the length of a text string"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which option in Excel allows you to create a drop-down list in a cell?",
    answer: "Data Validation",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "AutoFilter",
      "Sort and Filter",
      "Conditional Formatting"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which function is used to find the smallest value in a range in Excel?",
    answer: "MIN",
    options: [
      "MIN",
      "SMALL",
      "SMALLEST",
      "MINIMUM"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the Excel function 'HLOOKUP'?",
    answer: "Searches for a value in a horizontal row and returns a corresponding value from another row",
    options: [
      "Searches for a value in a horizontal row and returns a corresponding value from another row",
      "Calculates the sum of values in a vertical column",
      "Performs a horizontal text alignment",
      "Converts a number into hexadecimal format"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, what does the 'NOW' function return?",
    answer: "The current date and time",
    options: [
      "The current date and time",
      "The current date",
      "The current time",
      "The number of cells in a range"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How can you freeze the top row and first column in Excel so that they remain visible while scrolling?",
    answer: "Use the 'Freeze Panes' option under the 'View' tab.",
    options: [
      "Apply conditional formatting to the top row and first column.",
      "Use the 'Freeze Panes' option under the 'View' tab.",
      "Right-click and choose 'Freeze Top Row' and 'Freeze First Column.'",
      "Use the 'Lock Cells' option in the 'Format' menu."
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which Excel function returns the current row number of a cell?",
    answer: "ROW",
    options: [
      "CELLROW",
      "ROW",
      "ROWNUM",
      "CURRENTROW"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'Goal Seek' feature in Excel allow you to do?",
    answer: "Set a target value for a formula and find the input value needed to achieve it",
    options: [
      "Find and replace specific text in a worksheet",
      "Set a target value for a formula and find the input value needed to achieve it",
      "Perform complex statistical analysis",
      "Create a chart or graph from data"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In Excel, what does the 'SUBTOTAL' function do?",
    answer: "Provides a subtotal for a filtered list",
    options: [
      "Returns the sum of a range of values",
      "Provides a subtotal for a filtered list",
      "Calculates the difference between two dates",
      "Multiplies two numbers together"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which Excel function is used to count the number of unique values in a range?",
    answer: "UNIQUE",
    options: [
      "COUNT",
      "COUNTIF",
      "UNIQUE",
      "DISTINCTCOUNT"
    ]
  },

  // Windows Shortcut
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to open the Task Manager in Windows?",
    answer: "Ctrl + Shift + Esc",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + Shift + Esc",
      "Ctrl + Alt + Del",
      "Win + Tab",
      "Alt + F4"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key allows you to minimize all open windows and show the desktop?",
    answer: "Win + D",
    options: [
      "Win + D",
      "Alt + Tab",
      "Ctrl + A",
      "Win + E"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How do you lock your computer quickly using a shortcut key?",
    answer: "Win + L",
    options: [
      "Win + L",
      "Alt + F4",
      "Ctrl + Alt + Del",
      "Win + U"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to rename a selected file or folder in Windows?",
    answer: "F2",
    options: [
      "F2",
      "Ctrl + R",
      "Alt + Enter",
      "Shift + R"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To open the Run dialog box, you can use which shortcut key?",
    answer: "Win + R",
    options: [
      "Win + R",
      "Ctrl + R",
      "Alt + R",
      "Shift + R"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key allows you to switch between open applications or windows?",
    answer: "Alt + Tab",
    options: [
      "Alt + Tab",
      "Win + Tab",
      "Ctrl + Tab",
      "Shift + Tab"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How do you take a screenshot of the current window using a shortcut key?",
    answer: "Alt + Print Screen",
    options: [
      "Alt + Print Screen",
      "Win + Shift + S",
      "Ctrl + S",
      "F12"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to undo the last action in many Windows applications?",
    answer: "Ctrl + Z",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + Z",
      "Ctrl + U",
      "Alt + Z",
      "Win + Z"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To close the active window, which shortcut key can you use?",
    answer: "Alt + F4",
    options: [
      "Alt + F4",
      "Ctrl + W",
      "Win + C",
      "Shift + F4"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key lets you cycle through the open tabs or documents in your web browser or application?",
    answer: "Ctrl + Tab",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + Tab",
      "Alt + F4",
      "Win + Tab",
      "Shift + Tab"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How do you cut selected text or files using a shortcut key?",
    answer: "Ctrl + X",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + X",
      "Alt + X",
      "Win + X",
      "Shift + X"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to open the Windows Explorer (File Explorer) in Windows?",
    answer: "Win + E",
    options: [
      "Win + E",
      "Alt + E",
      "Ctrl + E",
      "F4"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key allows you to paste the copied content using a shortcut key?",
    answer: "Ctrl + V",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + V",
      "Alt + V",
      "Win + V",
      "Shift + V"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To open the Windows Settings app, which shortcut key should you use?",
    answer: "Win + I",
    options: [
      "Win + I",
      "Ctrl + S",
      "Alt + S",
      "Shift + I"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How do you navigate between the items on the desktop or Start menu using a shortcut key?",
    answer: "Arrow keys",
    options: [
      "Arrow keys",
      "Ctrl + Arrow keys",
      "Win + Arrow keys",
      "Alt + Arrow keys"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to open the context menu for a selected item in Windows?",
    answer: "Shift + F10",
    options: [
      "Shift + F10",
      "Ctrl + F10",
      "Win + F10",
      "Alt + F10"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which shortcut key combination is used to close a tab in most web browsers?",
    answer: "Ctrl + W",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + W",
      "Alt + F4",
      "Win + W",
      "Shift + W"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To open the Action Center in Windows, you can use which shortcut key?",
    answer: "Win + A",
    options: [
      "Win + A",
      "Ctrl + A",
      "Alt + A",
      "F5"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the shortcut key to switch between virtual desktops in Windows?",
    answer: "Ctrl + Win + Left/Right",
    options: [
      "Ctrl + Win + Left/Right",
      "Alt + Win + Up/Down",
      "Shift + Win + 1/2/3...",
      "Win + Alt + V"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "To quickly open the Windows Task View to manage open applications and virtual desktops, which shortcut key should you use?",
    answer: "Win + Tab",
    options: [
      "Win + Tab",
      "Alt + Tab",
      "Ctrl + Tab",
      "Shift + Tab"
    ]
  },

  // Computer Hardware
  {
    question: "What type of computer memory is non-volatile and retains data even when the power is turned off?",
    answer: "ROM",
    options: [
      "RAM",
      "ROM",
      "Cache",
      "CPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which component of a CPU is responsible for performing arithmetic and logic operations?",
    answer: "ALU (Arithmetic Logic Unit)",
    options: [
      "Control Unit",
      "ALU (Arithmetic Logic Unit)",
      "Register",
      "Cache"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary function of a GPU (Graphics Processing Unit)?",
    answer: "Render graphics and images",
    options: [
      "Execute program instructions",
      "Manage system memory",
      "Render graphics and images",
      "Store data temporarily"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of storage device uses spinning platters to store data?",
    answer: "HDD (Hard Disk Drive)",
    options: [
      "SSD (Solid-State Drive)",
      "HDD (Hard Disk Drive)",
      "USB flash drive",
      "CD-ROM"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does RAID stand for in the context of data storage?",
    answer: "Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks",
    options: [
      "Random Array of Independent Disks",
      "Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks",
      "Rapid Access and Instant Data",
      "Relational Analysis of Integrated Data"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of motherboard slot is commonly used for high-performance graphics cards?",
    answer: "PCIe",
    options: [
      "PCI",
      "AGP",
      "PCIe",
      "ISA"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What does BIOS stand for in the context of a computer?",
    answer: "Basic Input/Output System",
    options: [
      "Basic Input/Output System",
      "Binary Input/Output System",
      "Basic Integrated Operating System",
      "Bootloader Input/Output System"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which component is responsible for managing the power supply and distributing power to various hardware components in a computer?",
    answer: "PSU (Power Supply Unit)",
    options: [
      "CPU",
      "PSU (Power Supply Unit)",
      "RAM",
      "GPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary function of a Northbridge chip on a motherboard?",
    answer: "Connect the CPU to high-speed components",
    options: [
      "Manage data storage",
      "Control power distribution",
      "Connect the CPU to high-speed components",
      "Handle network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of monitor technology uses organic compounds that emit light when an electric current is applied?",
    answer: "OLED (Organic Light-Emitting Diode)",
    options: [
      "LCD (Liquid Crystal Display)",
      "CRT (Cathode Ray Tube)",
      "OLED (Organic Light-Emitting Diode)",
      "LED (Light-Emitting Diode)"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary purpose of a sound card in a computer?",
    answer: "Process and output audio",
    options: [
      "Display graphics",
      "Control power supply",
      "Process and output audio",
      "Manage network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of port is commonly used for connecting external hard drives and other peripherals?",
    answer: "USB",
    options: [
      "VGA",
      "USB",
      "HDMI",
      "DVI"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which component is responsible for temporarily storing data that is actively being processed by the CPU?",
    answer: "RAM",
    options: [
      "Hard drive",
      "RAM",
      "GPU",
      "Monitor"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary function of a UPS (Uninterruptible Power Supply) in a computer setup?",
    answer: "Provide backup power during outages",
    options: [
      "Store data",
      "Enhance graphics performance",
      "Provide backup power during outages",
      "Manage network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which component is responsible for translating virtual memory addresses to physical memory addresses in a computer's memory management unit (MMU)?",
    answer: "TLB (Translation Lookaside Buffer)",
    options: [
      "ALU",
      "CPU",
      "TLB (Translation Lookaside Buffer)",
      "RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary function of a NIC (Network Interface Carin a computer?",
    answer: "Connect the computer to a network",
    options: [
      "Process graphics",
      "Store operating system files",
      "Connect the computer to a network",
      "Control power supply"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of port is commonly used to connect an external keyboard and mouse to a computer?",
    answer: "USB",
    options: [
      "USB",
      "HDMI",
      "DisplayPort",
      "Thunderbolt"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of a CMOS battery on a motherboard?",
    answer: "Maintain BIOS settings",
    options: [
      "Power the CPU",
      "Maintain BIOS settings",
      "Improve graphics performance",
      "Manage network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of storage device is known for its extremely fast read and write speeds and has no moving parts?",
    answer: "SSD (Solid-State Drive)",
    options: [
      "HDD (Hard Disk Drive)",
      "SSD (Solid-State Drive)",
      "CD-ROM",
      "Floppy disk"
    ]
  },



  // {
  //   question: ``,
  //   answer: "",
  //   options: [
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     ""
  //   ]
  // },
  // {
  //   question: ``,
  //   answer: "",
  //   options: [
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     ""
  //   ]
  // },
  // {
  //   question: ``,
  //   answer: "",
  //   options: [
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     "",
  //     ""
  //   ]
  // },




];

// Shuffle the questions array randomly and update the 'numb' property
shuffleArray(questions);

// Track which questions have been displayed
const displayedQuestions = [];

// Function to get the next question without repetition
function getNextQuestion() {
  if (displayedQuestions.length === questions.length) {
    // All questions have been displayed
    return null;
  }
  let randomIndex;
  do {
    randomIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length);
  } while (displayedQuestions.includes(randomIndex));
  displayedQuestions.push(randomIndex);
  return questions[randomIndex];
}

// Example of how to get the next question
const nextQuestion = getNextQuestion();
if (nextQuestion) {
  console.log(nextQuestion.question);
  console.log(nextQuestion.options);
} else {
  console.log("All questions have been displayed.");
}
